<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Qudus Abolade</title>
    <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Qudus Abolade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Operational Efficiency through Automation at RealEstatePro</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview The RealEstatePro Automation Project was initiated to address the challenge of manually processing large volumes of client emails and forms, which was time-consuming and error-prone. This project aimed to automate the extraction of relevant data and documents, thereby speeding up response times and reducing human error.
Objectives Enhance Efficiency: Automate repetitive tasks to allow staff to focus on higher-value activities. Improve Accuracy: Minimize manual entry errors by automating data extraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Time-Off Automation</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Every year, employees are entitled to 22 working days of paid time off (PTO). The objective of this project is to implement an automated system for managing employee time-off processing within the organization. This system aims to streamline the application and approval of time-off requests, ensuring efficient communication between employees and their managers.
Objectives The key objectives of this project are:
Utilize Airtable as the database to store and manage time-off requests, approval status, and leave days balances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D.A.R.T.H - Digital Assistant for Resourceful Technical Help</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>D.A.R.T.H is a powerful Streamlit application designed to assist developers in enhancing their coding experience. With a focus on providing valuable resources and aiding in various aspects of coding, D.A.R.T.H offers four key functions to make developers&amp;rsquo; lives easier.
Features Article Generation:
Generates articles in English, Yoruba, Igbo, and Hausa. Synthesizes English articles into speech for accessibility. Code Documentation Generator:
Simplifies the process of creating code documentation. Generates comprehensive documentation for provided code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scones Unlimited ML Workflow with SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview Image Classifiers play a crucial role in computer vision applications across various industries. As a Machine Learning Engineer at Scones Unlimited, I could be tasked with developing an image classification model to optimize logistics operations.
Project Introduction The goal is to build an image classification model capable of distinguishing between bicycles and motorcycles. This model will aid in routing delivery professionals efficiently, contributing to Scones Unlimited&amp;rsquo;s operational optimization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Style Transfer App</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>The Neural Style Transfer Art App is an innovative project developed to harness the power of Neural Style Transfer (NST) technology for creating captivating artistic transformations. This application showcases the fusion of art and artificial intelligence to enable users to apply artistic styles to their images and videos.
Techniques and Tools Utilized Neural Style Transfer Deep Learning PyTorch and TensorFlow (deep learning frameworks) Python Functionality The app offers two distinct modes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landmark Classification &amp; Tagging for Social Media</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The Landmark Classifier project combines AI and image recognition to identify landmarks in photos. Built using Python, this supervised machine learning endeavor showcases the power of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to predict locations depicted in images, transforming photo-sharing experiences.
Techniques and Tools Employed Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) Python Image Recognition Transfer Learning Streamlit (for building the interactive app) Dataset The dataset encompasses a diverse range of images showcasing landmarks. This dataset forms the backbone for training the landmark classifier and enabling it to recognize and predict various landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handwritten Digits Classifier</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The Handwritten Digits Classifier is a deep learning project built with PyTorch to recognize and classify handwritten digits. The primary goal of this project is to prototype an Optical Character Recognition (OCR) system that can accurately identify and interpret handwritten characters.
Techniques and Tools Used Deep Learning Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) Python PyTorch (deep learning framework) Dataset The classifier has been trained on the famous MNIST database of handwritten digits, which contains a large dataset of labeled images of handwritten numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict Bike Sharing Demand</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The Bike Sharing Demand prediction project using AutoGluon is about building and training machine learning models to predict the demand for bike-sharing services. The project involves analyzing and preprocessing data from CSV files provided by the Kaggle competition. By leveraging the capabilities of AutoGluon&amp;rsquo;s Tabular Prediction, I engineered additional features, fine-tuned hyperparameters, and experimented with various models to achieve the most accurate predictions. The ultimate goal is to accurately forecast the demand for bike-sharing services, which can be valuable for companies like Uber, Lyft, and DoorDash to optimize their operations and provide better customer service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake News Classifier</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The Fake News Classifier is a supervised machine learning project built with Python to classify news articles as either real or fake. The primary goal of this project is to prototype a fake news detection system that can accurately identify and flag fake news articles. The model uses natural language processing techniques to extract features from the text of the articles and applies a classification algorithm to predict the class of each article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flower Species Image Classifier Application</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 14:51:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Flower Species Image Classifier is a deep learning project designed to identify different species of flowers from images. Leveraging the power of convolutional neural networks (CNNs), this image classifier has been trained on a diverse dataset containing images of various flower species. The trained CNN model can accurately predict the species of a flower given an input image.
Techniques and Tools Used Deep Learning Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) Python TensorFlow or PyTorch (deep learning frameworks) Dataset The project utilizes a large dataset of flower images, carefully labeled with their respective species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Classifier to Identify Dog Breeds</title>
      <link>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qudus4l.github.io/portfolio_q/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>This project is an image classifier that can identify different breeds of dogs using deep learning techniques. The classifier is based on a convolutional neural network (CNN) that has been trained on a large dataset of dog images. The CNN is trained to recognize 133 different dog breeds, and can be used to predict the breed of a dog given an image of a dog. If the image is of a human, the CNN will identify the resembling dog breed or identify it as some other animal like a cat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
